

# SON CAO

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER, DEVOPS ENGINEER, AUTOMATION ENGINEER 

• HA NOI, VIET NAM • 0855188833

#### • DETAILS •

124/73/7 Au Co Street Ha Noi Viet Nam 0855188833 caothanhson48@gmail.com

Date of birth 04/08/1991

SKILLS

Cloud, Azure, AWS, GCP

Docker, Nomad, Kubernetes

Terraform, Ansible

Python, Linux

#### PROFILE

I have over 9 years of extensive experience in the IT industry, having fulfilled various roles such as Automation Engineer, System Engineer, DevOps Engineer, Quality Assurance Engineer, and Technical Support. I am passionate about ensuring smooth operations and finding the right balance between manual and automated processes. Whether working independently or collaboratively within a team, I am confident in my abilities. I possess a strong aptitude for quickly learning new technologies and am eager to take on challenging tasks

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Site Reliability Engineer at Xendit

June 2022 — January 2024

- Implemented a spot EKS Nodegroup infrastructure that reduced EKS infrastructure costs by 10%
- Plan and perform cluster upgrades for approximately a dozens EKS clusters regularly
- Establish an mTLS connection between Shopify and a third-party integration service, utilizing Cloudflare. manage WAF rules, including rate limiting and IP whitelisting, to meet security requirements
- On-call Duty every 2 month becoming the primary responder for all ad-hoc requests and emergencies, join the war room and contribute to vary postmoterm action
- Utilizing Datadog and Splunk, analyzed system performance, identified and troubleshooted issues, and implemented solutions to enhance system throughput.
   Additionally, created Datadog dashboards and custom metrics to monitor ad hoc metrics such as domain and certificate expiry
- Support the product team and mentor other colleagues, actively participating in PR reviews to ensure that best practices, coding standards, and project requirements are followed
- Contribute to the regional migration service from Oregon to the SG region for various product teams, transitioning from RabbitMQ to Kafka and AWS SQS
- Provide guidance to the product team on utilizing Kubernetes such as Ingress, Jobs, CronJobs, resource utilization.
- Contribute to the team's Terraform module and Helm chart. Implement IAC
  following a team-centric strategy to enable product teams to self-serve provision
  various resources, and manage their team permissions

#### DevOps Engineer / Site Reliability Engineer at One Mount Group, Ha Noi

December 2019 — April 2022

- Design and setup infrastructure CI/CD pipeline for new development project.
- Making improvement about workflow, pipeline, build speed, architecture, system reliability, monitoring.
- Support and troubleshooting infrastructure, environment, network, deployment and runtime issue
- Migrate services from DC to Google Cloud.
- Build and maintain centralized DevOps tools

#### DevOps Engineer at Niteco, Ha Noi

March 2019 — December 2019

- Setup DevOps life cycle and Managed Services process
- Proactive handle and support client via the ticket system and on-call
- · Design and build up system architecture on Cloud

## Automation Engineer for Telstra at FPT Software, Ha Noi

March 2018 — March 2019

- Manage and optimize infrastructure and enterprise applications, satisfy all stakeholders.
- Respond to high severity production issues escalated by operations teams
- · Contribute to the migration strategy of Atlassian applications to AWS
- Work closely with the development team to ensure the successful deployment and operation of their application.
- Support thousands of users in the Atlassian ecosystem: Tools configuration, problem investigating, suggest best practice.

## AWS Cloud Engineer for Essent at FPT Software, Ha Noi

June 2017 — March 2019

- Manage and operate a large scale system on AWS
- Monitoring Infrastructure, Application 24/7
- Contribute to system architecture design.
- Technical support for client
- · Proactively monitoring customer system and application

#### Quality Assurance Engineer, Ha Noi

2015 - 2017

- · Working on Product Kofax Total Agility and Kofax Front Office Server
- Study requirement and design test case, test charter, test script. Run daily Automation test and manual test.
- Maintain Test Environment in the Azure cloud.
- Support developer in fixing bug and troubleshoot problem,
- · Daily Report and communicate with team in USA.

## EDUCATION

Bachelor, Genetic Bach Khoa, Ha Noi

2009 - 2014

## CERTIFICATION

Microsoft Certified Azure DevOps Engineer Expert

August 2019 — August 2021

**Microsoft Certified Azure Solution Architect Expert** 

May 2019 — May 2021

**Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator Associate** 

July 2019 — July 2021

## **AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate**

December 2017 — December 2020

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/b2470cfb-b672-439d-a7b1-41b9b9133c8b/public\_url